Guide to the Pettigrew Papers
Yale University Library
- General Correspondence Files, 1797-1865; Series I:; 4.59' (13 boxes)
  - Todd, Henry John, 1763-1845. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1825 or later] (Box 11, Folder 535)
    On one of Pettigrew's books.
  - Tonna, Lewis Hippolytus Joseph, 1812-1857. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Jan-May (Box 11, Folder 536)
    On a lecture given by Pettigrew and an exhibition of a mummy from Thebes.
  - Torrens, Robert. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1824-25 (Box 11, Folder 537)
    Letters discuss medical matters pertaining to appointments in various London hospitals.
  - Townley, James, 1774-1833. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1828 Jul 12 (Box 11, Folder 538)
  - Toynbee, Joseph, 1815-1866. ALS to [T. J.] Pettigrew, [1841 or later] (Box 11, Folder 539)
    Asks for Pettigrew's father's support during his balloting for admittance into the Royal Society.
  - Traherne, John Montgomery, 1788-1860. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1846 Apr 22 (Box 11, Folder 540)
  - Travers, Benjamin, 1783-1858. 4 ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1828 Mar (Box 11, Folder 541)
    On medical matters and Traver's published works.
  - Tupper, Martin Farquhar, 1810-1889. 6 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-54 (Box 11, Folder 542)
    Letters discuss Tupper's membership in the British Archaeological Assn. and a book of Pettigrew's which Tupper edited. The letters are written in a whimsical manner, even when noting the death of one of his children.
  - Turnbull, William. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 543)
    On the death of Turnbull's son in India of cholera.
  - Turner, Charles, 1774-1857. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1825], 1831 (Box 11, Folder 544)
  - Turner, Dawson, 1755-1858. 22 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1840-52 (Box 11, Folder 545)
    On Hudson Gurney, the Brit. Arch. Assoc. and its rivalry with the Arch. Inst., Pettigrew's disagreement with the Soc. of Antiquaries, the deaths of Sophia Gooch Manby and William Dawson Hooker, and Sir Joseph Dalton Hooker's expedition to Antarctica.
  - Turner, Sir Tomkyns Hilgrove, 1766?-1843. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1838-41 (Box 11, Folder 546)
  - Tuthill, Sir George Leman, 1772-1835. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1824, 1835 (Box 11, Folder 547)
  - Tymms, Samuel, 1808-1871. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Feb 2 (Box 11, Folder 548)
  - Tyrrell, Frederick, 1793-1843. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1828], 1834 (Box 11, Folder 549)
    One letter asks for Pettigrew's help in electing Williamson Coulson Surgeon to the Aldersgate St. Dispensary.
  - Upham, Edward, 1776-1834. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1829 or later] (Box 12, Folder 550)
    On antiquarian matters. Upham notes that he has "escaped altogether this wide spreading epidemic."
  - Ure, Andrew, 1778-1857. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew (Box 12, Folder 551)
  - Uwins, David, 1780?-1837. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 552)
  - Valpy, Richard, 1754-1836. 8 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1817-26 (Box 12, Folder 553)
    On Reading School's triennial visitation by various officials including the Duke of Sussex.
  - Vigors, Nicholas Aylward, 1785-1840. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827, 1828 (Box 12, Folder 554)
    Sends a plan of the gardens of the Zoological Society to the Duke of Sussex.
  - Vulliamy, Lewis, 1791-1871. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew (Box 12, Folder 555)
  - Wadd, Thomas M. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 556)
    Mentions William Wadd.
  - Waddington, George, 1793-1869. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 1841-52 (Box 12, Folder 557)
  - Wallich, Nathaniel, 1786-1854. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830-50 (Box 12, Folder 558)
    One letter introduces Dr. Brandis, lecturer in Botany from the University of Bonn.
  - Warburton, Henry, 1784?-1858. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1825 Mar 4 (Box 12, Folder 559)
  - Ward, Edward Matthew, 1816-1879. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850, 1852 (Box 12, Folder 560)
    Discusses a testimonial for Robert Vernon.
  - Ward, James, 1769-1859. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Mar-Apr (Box 12, Folder 561)
    One letter discusses Ward's painting.
  - Wardrop, James, 1782-1869. 3 ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1838 or later] (Box 12, Folder 562)
  - Warne, Elizabeth. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 563)
    Mentions Charles Warne.
  - Warneford, Samuel Wilson, 1763-1855. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1848-50 (Box 12, Folder 564)
    On the health of a favorite niece.
  - Watson, Ralph. 9 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-33 (Box 12, Folder 565)
    On Watson's plan for rescuing foundering ships (cf. George Manby).
  - Way, Albert. 1805-1874. 6 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1844 May (Box 12, Folder 566)
    On several matters concerning the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Webster, Thomas, 1800-1886. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Jan 7 (Box 12, Folder 567)
    Agrees to subscribe to the testimonial for Robert Vernon.
  - Weld, Charles Richard, 1813-1869. ALS and LS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849, 1852 (Box 12, Folder 568)
  - Wellbeloved, Charles, 1769-1858.
    - 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845, 1852 (Box 12, Folder 569)
    - ALS to C. R. Smith, 1849 Dec 27 (Box 12, Folder 570)
  - Wemyss, David Douglas, 1760-1839. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1828 Feb 27 (Box 12, Folder 571)
    Mentions the death of General Ogg.
  - Westall, Richard, 1765-1836. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1827]-29 (Box 12, Folder 572)
  - Westmacott, Sir Richard, 1775-1856. 14 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1 ALS to T[homas?] Taylor, 1 ALS to [W.R. Hamilton], 1816-43 (Box 12, Folder 573)
    On Westmacott's lectures at the Royal Academy. 2 signed tickets to the lecture are included.
  - Westmacott, Richard, 1799-1872. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1844 Jan 11 (Box 12, Folder 574)
  - Wharncliffe, Edward Montagu-Stuart- Wortley Mackenzie, 1st Earl of, 1827-1899. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1862 Mar 14 (Box 12, Folder 575)
    Declines the presidency of the British Archaeological Association's congress at Leeds.
  - Whatton, William Robert, 1790-1835. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827 Jul 6 (Box 12, Folder 576)
    Mentions a proposed work by Whatton and states that Charles Sumner had served as Librarian to George IV.
  - Wheatley, J. H. W. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831 Jan 15 (Box 12, Folder 577)
    Seeks permission to dedicate his translation of Condillac's Universal History to the Duke of Sussex.
  - Whichcord, John, 1823-1885. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Jun 21 (Box 12, Folder 578)
  - Whittaker, George Byrom, 1793-1847. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1824 May 13 (Box 12, Folder 579)
  - Whittaker, John William, 1790?-1854. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850-52 (Box 12, Folder 580)
    Letter discusses several of Whittaker's papers.
  - Wilbraham, Roger, 1744-1829. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1825-27 (Box 12, Folder 581)
  - Wild, Charles, 1781-1835. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1828 Apr 12 (Box 12, Folder 582)
    Discusses an exhibition presented by the Society of Painters in Water Colours.
  - Wilkins, George, 1785-1865. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1852 Sep 6 (Box 12, Folder 583)
    On Arthur Ashpital's and James Francis Dimrock's works on Southwell Church.
  - Wilkins, William, 1778-1839. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826 Feb (Box 12, Folder 584)
  - Wilkinson, Sir John Gardner, 1797-1875. 91 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1830]-58 (Box 12, Folder 585-590)
    On Wilkinson's deteriorating health and his travels; James Haliburton's meloncholy state, possibly due to opium. Included is a holograph essay, "On an Early Mosaic in St. Marks representing the removal of the body of the evangelist to Venice" (1851). Many of the letters contain drawings and hieroglyphics. Many are signed pseudonymously and addressed to "Peti-jou" or other variants of Pettigrew.
  - Williams, John, 1811-1862. 1 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew, 1851 Oct 23 (Box 13, Folder 591)
    Accompanied by a prospectus and list of subscribers to William's translation of The Gododin.
  - Willis, Robert, 1800-1875. 1 AL to Sir John Gardner Wilkinson, 1850 Jan 19 (Box 13, Folder 592)
    Wishes to subscribe to Wilkinson's Architecture of Egypt.
  - Willson, Edward James, 1787-1854. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1852 Jul 30 (Box 13, Folder 593)
    On a proposed visit to Lincoln by the British Archaeological Assn.
  - Wilson, Sir Daniel, 1816-1892. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Jul 12 (Box 13, Folder 594)
    Wilson is unable to participate in the Manchester congress of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Wilson, James Arthur, 1795-1882. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1836 or later] (Box 13, Folder 595)
  - Wilson, Matthew. 4 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1850 or later] (Box 13, Folder 596)
    Discusses Wilson's re-election to Parliament in one letter.
  - Woodfall, George, 1767-1844. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-34 (Box 13, Folder 597)
  - Word, J. ALS and LS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1836 Sep, Nov (Box 13, Folder 598)
    Solicits Pettigrew's subscription for the Metropolitan Conservative Journal and includes a prospectus for it.
  - Wrangham, Francis, 1769-1842. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1816-30 (Box 13, Folder 599)
    On Wrangham's books, Dr. Lettsom, and the Royal Sea Bathing Infirmary at Margate, for which Wrangham claims to "take to myself the credit of having established it."
  - Wright, John, 1770?-1844. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1842 or later] (Box 13, Folder 600)
    On Wright's health.
  - Wright, Thomas, 1810-1877. 10 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1840-45 (Box 13, Folder 601)
    On works by Pettigrew and Wright, the activities of the British Archaeological Association, and its competition with the Archaeological Institute.
  - Wynyard, Miss. AL to Mr. Stephenson, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 602)
  - Wyon, William, 1795-1851. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1832, 1840 (Box 13, Folder 603)
    Letter discusses a medal Wyon is to engrave.
  - Yeats, Grant David, 1773-1836. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826 May 1 (Box 13, Folder 604)
  - Yorke, Charles Philip, 1764-1834. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1817 Feb 3 (Box 13, Folder 605)
  - Yorke, Sir Joseph Sidney, 1768-1831. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1820 Sep 1 (Box 13, Folder 606)
  - Youatt, William, 1776-1847. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1828-35 (Box 13, Folder 607)
    Invites Pettigrew to become an honorary member of the Veterinary Medical Society in one letter.
  - Young, Sir Charles George, 1795-1869. 5 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1853 Mar (Box 13, Folder 608)
  - Young, G. 5 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew, 1833-49 (Box 13, Folder 609)
  - Zouche, Robert Curzon, 14th Baron, 1810-1873. AL to [T. J. Pettigrew], 1849 Jan 22 (Box 13, Folder 610)
    Agrees to subscribe to a work by Sir John Gardner Wilkinson.
- Additional Correspondence, 1803-1865; Series II.; 2.5' (9 boxes)
  Series II, Additional Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Box 21 contains personal papers, alphabetically arranged.
  - Ackermann, M., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 611)
    "Enigma": Autograph MS Poem
  - Adames, T., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 612)
  - Adams, H., 1853 (Box 14, Folder 613)
  - Addijn, Dr., [1830] (Box 14, Folder 614)
  - Aibell, J.H., 1861 (Box 14, Folder 615)
  - Alexander, Henry, 1831 (Box 14, Folder 616)
  - Alison, Somerville Scott, 1861 (Box 14, Folder 617)
  - Allen, William, [1856] (Box 14, Folder 618)
    ALS to J.R. Planché
  - Amhurst, W., 1861 (Box 14, Folder 619)
  - Andrewes, Gerard Thomas, 1841 (Box 14, Folder 620)
  - Annesley, J., 1839-45 (Box 14, Folder 621)
  - Arlking, George, 1852 (Box 14, Folder 622)
  - Armstrong, John, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 623)
  - Arnachellam, J., [1831] (Box 14, Folder 624)
  - Arnold, S.J., 1822-31 (Box 14, Folder 625)
  - Arnott, James M., 1829-35 (Box 14, Folder 626)
  - Arthur, George, 1849 (Box 14, Folder 627)
  - Baillie, Hugh, [1828]-33 (Box 14, Folder 628)
  - Baldwin, Charles Barry, 1836 (Box 14, Folder 629)
  - Barker, T. Herbert, 1848 (Box 14, Folder 630)
  - Barme, John, 1830 (Box 14, Folder 631)
  - Barnwell, Charles Frederick, [1839?] (Box 14, Folder 632)
  - Barry, Dr., 1828 (Box 14, Folder 633)
  - Barry, Mr. [M], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 634)
  - Bathurst, F.H., 1858 (Box 14, Folder 635)
  - Beale, Lionel, 1862 (Box 14, Folder 636)
  - Beatty, William, 1834 (Box 14, Folder 637)
  - Bedford, Duchess of, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 638)
  - Beesley, J., 1850 (Box 14, Folder 639)
  - Bell, William, 1850 (Box 14, Folder 640)
  - Beloe, George, [1818?] (Box 14, Folder 641)
  - Bene, Samuel, 1842 (Box 14, Folder 642)
  - Benham, [R.H.D.], 1846 (Box 14, Folder 643)
  - Berlanga, Manuel Rodriguez de, 1862 (Box 14, Folder 644)
    AL in Latin to President of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Berry, Titus, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 645)
  - Bert, H.P., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 646)
  - Bessborough, Lady, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 647)
  - Bingham, C.W., [1847]-51 (Box 14, Folder 648)
  - Birago, Comte Mezza Barba, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 649)
    ALS in French, and Calling card
  - Birch, [S.], 1849 (Box 14, Folder 650)
    ALS to Dr. Lee
  - Black, Dr., 1828-[29] (Box 14, Folder 651)
  - Blair, Robert, 1830 (Box 14, Folder 652)
  - Blakiston, Peyton, 1856 (Box 14, Folder 653)
  - Bland, George, 1851 (Box 14, Folder 654)
    with ALS of same date from Mrs. Bland to T.J. Pettigrew.
  - Bligh, General, 1829 (Box 14, Folder 655)
  - Blundell, B., 1850 (Box 14, Folder 656)
  - Blundell, E.S., 1833 (Box 14, Folder 657)
  - Blussé, S.J., 1835 (Box 14, Folder 658)
    ALS in French
  - Bosworth, Joseph, 1848 (Box 14, Folder 659)
  - Boughton, Mr. [Bruce], 1860 (Box 14, Folder 660)
  - Bowles, 1851 (Box 14, Folder 661)
  - Bowman, [William], 1851 (Box 14, Folder 662)
  - Brady, Col., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 663)
  - Brandon, Hamilton (Box 15, Folder 664)
  - Branner, Lt. Col., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 665)
  - Brigdon, Mr., [1830-1] (Box 15, Folder 666)
  - Briggins, Lady, [1818 or later] (Box 15, Folder 667)
  - Briggs, Lt. Col., 1829 (Box 15, Folder 668)
  - Brock, Edgar P., 1861 (Box 15, Folder 669)
  - Brooke, F.C., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 670)
    ALS to Sir Gardner
  - Brooke, John, 1860 (Box 15, Folder 671)
  - Brougham, W., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 672)
    ALS to Mr. Stephenson
  - Broughton, Col., [1829 or later] (Box 15, Folder 673)
  - [Brown, K.], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 674)
  - Browne, Harold, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 675)
  - Bruce, [W.D.], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 676)
  - Bruce-Pryce, John Bruce, [1847] (Box 15, Folder 677)
  - Buller, James W., 1861 (Box 15, Folder 678)
  - Bullett, A., 1850 (Box 15, Folder 679)
  - Bunne, G.A., 1832 (Box 15, Folder 680)
  - Bunsen, H.G., 1860 (Box 15, Folder 681)
    ALS to Pettigrew written on TL invitation to Church of England Book Hawking Union annual meeting and dinner.
  - Buonett, W., 1845 (Box 15, Folder 682)
  - Burne, John, [1848] (Box 15, Folder 683)
  - [Burton, Ryder], 1848 (Box 15, Folder 684)
    ALS to S. Cartwright
  - [Butterworth], Joshua, 1852 (Box 15, Folder 685)
  - Byerley, John, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 686)
  - Campanari, D.E., [1841 or later] (Box 15, Folder 687)
  - Carden, [Robert W.], 1858 (Box 15, Folder 688)
  - [Carking?], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 689)
  - Cartward, J.B., [1848 or later] (Box 15, Folder 690)
  - Cartwright, J., 1849 (Box 15, Folder 691)
  - Ceely, Robert, 1839 (Box 15, Folder 692)
  - Celm, Kerry, 1823 (Box 15, Folder 693)
    AL to the Duke of Sussex
  - Chalklen, Charles, 1845 (Box 15, Folder 694)
  - Champion, [1860 or later] (Box 15, Folder 695)
  - Chatterton, [Sir] W[illiam], 1847 (Box 15, Folder 696)
  - Chevalier, Mr. [Thomas William], 1833 (Box 15, Folder 697)
  - Churchill, Lord John, 1835 (Box 15, Folder 698)
  - Clifford, [H.M.], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 699)
  - Clifford, Sophia de, [1822] (Box 15, Folder 700)
  - Clift, William, 1825 (Box 15, Folder 701)
  - Clitherow, Col., 1834 (Box 15, Folder 702)
  - [Coates, J.], 1860 (Box 15, Folder 703)
  - Cohery, M.J., 1835 (Box 15, Folder 704)
    3 ALS to Pettigrew, and 1 ALS to [Library G.O. York]
  - Cole, Robert, 1845-46 (Box 15, Folder 705)
  - Coleman, Ch[arles], 1828-33 (Box 15, Folder 706)
  - Colinde, John Duke, 1861 (Box 15, Folder 707)
  - Colmache, Georgina, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 708)
  - [Colman], [1854 or later] (Box 15, Folder 709)
    ALS to G.I. French
  - [Colpey, H.], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 710)
  - Coltrine, M. Ridley, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 711)
  - Coningham, William, 1858 (Box 15, Folder 712)
  - Conolly, Lady Louisa, 1817 (Box 15, Folder 713)
    AL to "the Gentlemen that call'd from St. James's Church" and AL to "The Office of the Humane Society"
  - Conroy, Sir John, [1822-37] (Box 15, Folder 714)
    6 ALS, 1 AL, and 1 coversheet to T.J. Pettigrew. References to the Duchess of Kent and to Princess Victoria and vaccinations given her by Pettigrew.
  - Cook, Thomas, [1834]-1840 (Box 15, Folder 715)
  - Cooper, Bransby Blake, 1827-[1830] (Box 15, Folder 716)
  - Corbaux, Francis, 1829-33 (Box 15, Folder 717)
  - Cotton, H[enry] P[etty], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 718)
  - Coulthart, J. R[oss], 1850 (Box 15, Folder 719)
  - Crawford, A[dair], 1832 (Box 16, Folder 720)
  - Crewe, Sir John Harpur, 1850 (Box 16, Folder 721)
  - Crichton, A., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 722)
  - Croft, A.J., 1859 (Box 16, Folder 723)
  - Crombie, John, 1823 (Box 16, Folder 724)
  - Crosby, Rev. Robert, 1814 (Box 16, Folder 725)
  - Cuming, H. Syer, 1846-57 (Box 16, Folder 726)
    3 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew, and 2 ALS to Charles Roach Smith
  - Cunynghame, Mary, 1834 (Box 16, Folder 727)
    AL to [Dr. Crowne]
  - Curling, J.K., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 728)
  - D'Alton, John, 1860 (Box 16, Folder 729)
    ALS to [T.J. Pettigrew] written on Index for D'Altons "Illustrations of King James's Irish Army List."
  - d'Hoogvorst, [Joseph Marie], Baron [van der Linden] (Box 16, Folder 730)
  - [Dakins, W.], 1827 (Box 16, Folder 731)
  - Dale, R., 1834 (Box 16, Folder 732)
    1 ALS to [T.J. Pettigrew] and 1 ALS to Capt. James Mangles.
  - Dampier, Thomas, Bp. of Rochester, 1805 (Box 16, Folder 733)
    ALS to unidentified
  - Davids, [C], 1842 (Box 16, Folder 734)
  - Davidson, Thomas, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 735)
  - Davie, Sir H. Ferguson, bart., 1861 (Box 16, Folder 736)
  - Dawson, Nathaniel, 1849 (Box 16, Folder 737)
  - De Arabet, Baron, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 738)
  - De Gayangos, Mr. [Pascual], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 739)
  - De la Bire, Paul Bayoh, 1830 (Box 16, Folder 740)
  - De Nira, W., 1843 (Box 16, Folder 741)
    ALS in French to T.J. Pettigrew
  - Dean, J., 1827 (Box 16, Folder 742)
  - Deane, J.B., 1838 (Box 16, Folder 743)
  - Deans, Joseph, 1851 (Box 16, Folder 744)
  - Dearden, James, 1850 (Box 16, Folder 745)
  - DeCalliotte, Philip H., 1860 (Box 16, Folder 746)
  - [DeCappe], Daniel C., 1836-54 (Box 16, Folder 747)
  - Defuy, Lord, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 748)
  - DeSanity, Dr., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 749)
    Invitation in 3rd person, from Dr. Antommarchi and DeSanity, written and signed by DeSanity.
  - Desfontainen, [Mr.], 1818 (Box 16, Folder 750)
    ALS in French to T.J. Pettigrew.
  - Dewar, Rev. Dr. Daniel, 1831 (Box 16, Folder 751)
    ALS to T.J. Pettigrew, and 2 calling cards.
  - Digby, Henry, 1890 (Box 16, Folder 752)
    ALS to ?
  - Dollman, Francis T., 1860 (Box 16, Folder 753)
  - Don, [Thomas], [1816] (Box 16, Folder 754)
  - Doratt, [J], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 755)
  - Douglas, [William], 1816 (Box 16, Folder 756)
  - DuBois de Ferrières, M., 1854 (Box 16, Folder 757)
  - Duckworth, J.M., 1861 (Box 16, Folder 758)
  - Duke, Col., 1816 (Box 16, Folder 759)
  - Ebersaie, John von, 1849 (Box 16, Folder 760)
  - Edwardes. Henry, [1858 or later] (Box 16, Folder 761)
  - Ellis, [G.S.], 1845 (Box 16, Folder 762)
  - Ellis, J.J., 1842-50 (Box 16, Folder 763)
  - Elliston, J., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 764)
  - Elwin, R.J., 1828-29 (Box 16, Folder 765)
  - [Ephra--?], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 766)
  - Errington, John Richard, 1851-52 (Box 16, Folder 767)
  - Espinape, James, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 768)
  - Evans, John, 1861 (Box 16, Folder 769)
  - Evans, Robert, 1854 (Box 16, Folder 770)
  - Ewing, [W.], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 771)
  - Eyton, J. Walter, 1860 (Box 16, Folder 772)
  - Falerner, Mr., 1836 (Box 17, Folder 773)
  - Faulkner, Charles, 1860 (Box 17, Folder 774)
  - Faulkner, W.E.L., 1824 (Box 17, Folder 775)
  - Fawen, Stephen, 1846 (Box 17, Folder 776)
  - Fenton, J., 1850 (Box 17, Folder 777)
  - Fitzclarence, G., 1815-29 (Box 17, Folder 778)
  - Fitzgerald, William, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 779)
  - Fly, Dr., 1830 (Box 17, Folder 780)
  - Foggi, Prof., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 781)
  - Forrest, W., 1829 (Box 17, Folder 782)
  - Fowke, F., 1816 (Box 17, Folder 783)
  - [Fowler, Richard], n.d. (Box 17, Folder 784)
  - Frankland, Capt. (Box 17, Folder 785)
  - Fryer, Mr. [W.G.], [1831 or later] (Box 17, Folder 786)
  - Galeibis, T.A., [1855 or later] (Box 17, Folder 787)
  - Galway, Arundell, 1820 (Box 17, Folder 788)
  - Ganner, W.H., 1845 (Box 17, Folder 789)
  - Gardiner, C[harles], [1847 or later] (Box 17, Folder 790)
  - Gathurst, Clare, [1858-59] (Box 17, Folder 791)
  - Gilbert, Gilbert, 1833 (Box 17, Folder 792)
  - Gillham, [I.A.], 1838 (Box 17, Folder 793)
  - Glenlyon, Lord [Baron], n.d. (Box 17, Folder 794)
  - Glover, George, 1821-44 (Box 17, Folder 795)
  - Godwin, [Henry], 1859 (Box 17, Folder 796)
  - Gore, Edward, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 797)
  - Gosford, [William], n.d. (Box 17, Folder 798)
    ALS to [D. Shearman]
  - Grassini, Josephine, 1817 (Box 17, Folder 799)
    2 ALS in French to Mr. Major Magra
  - Gray, Eustace, 1859 (Box 17, Folder 800)
  - Gray, John Hamilton, 1860 (Box 17, Folder 801)
  - Greenshield, J.B., 1865 (Box 17, Folder 802)
    ALS to G.V. Irving
  - Gregory, Dr., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 803)
  - Grindlay, Capt. Melville (Box 17, Folder 804)
  - Grover, Capt., 1833 (Box 17, Folder 805)
  - Guard, Augustus, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 806)
  - Gunuing, William, 1836 (Box 17, Folder 807)
  - Haggard, William D., 1850 (Box 17, Folder 808)
  - Halford, [Thomas], [1847 or later] (Box 17, Folder 809)
  - Hamby, W., 1840 (Box 17, Folder 810)
  - Hanbury, Barnard, 1826-30 (Box 17, Folder 811)
  - Hapell, C.S., 1845 (Box 17, Folder 812)
  - Hardwicke, Thomas, 1833 (Box 17, Folder 813)
  - Hardy, Sir John, [1860 or later] (Box 17, Folder 814)
  - Harkness, H., 1826 (Box 17, Folder 815)
  - Harvey, Sir John, 1826 (Box 17, Folder 816)
  - Harvey, Thomas, 1856 (Box 17, Folder 817)
  - Hawess, W., 1853 (Box 17, Folder 818)
  - Hawkins, Dr. Bisset, [1828 or later] (Box 17, Folder 819)
  - Hawkins, Walter, 1856 (Box 17, Folder 820)
  - Heath, J.M., 1841 (Box 17, Folder 821)
  - Hehl, Frederick, 1857 (Box 17, Folder 822)
  - [Hemley], William, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 823)
  - Hemlow, J.S., 1846 (Box 17, Folder 824)
    ALS to Charles Roach Smith
  - Heurteloup, Baron, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 825)
  - Higgins, Col., 1832 (Box 17, Folder 826)
  - Hill, R[onald], n.d. (Box 17, Folder 827)
    ALS to Mssrs. Nichols & Bensley [John Gough Nichols?]
  - Hinrich, Sir Henry B., [1831 or later] (Box 17, Folder 828)
  - Hippisley, Henry, 1859 (Box 17, Folder 829)
  - Hooker, John, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 830)
  - Hope, G.W., 1859 (Box 17, Folder 831)
  - Houblon, Thomas Archer, [1858 or later] (Box 17, Folder 832)
  - Howitt, Thomas, 1850 (Box 17, Folder 833)
    1 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS to unknown 3rd party
  - Howship, John, [1829 or later] (Box 17, Folder 834)
  - Hughes, Thomas, 1856 (Box 17, Folder 835)
  - Hughes, Victor, 1852 (Box 17, Folder 836)
  - Hulbert, Daniel P.M., 1851 (Box 17, Folder 837)
    ALS to T.J. Pettigrew, with included Publishers' Notice of Hulberts work.
  - Hussey, James, 1858 (Box 17, Folder 838)
  - Hutchinson, Peter Orlando, 1861-62 (Box 17, Folder 839)
    2 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew. 1 ALS to Rev. Dr. George Oliver, with attached ALS from G. Oliver to Mr. Drake, written two days later.
  - Hutchinson, A. Copland, 1833-34 (Box 17, Folder 840)
  - Irindlay, [R.], 1829 (Box 17, Folder 841)
  - Irving, M., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 842)
  - Irwin, Capt., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 843)
  - Isaac, P., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 844)
  - Isaacs, George, 1848-50 (Box 17, Folder 845)